JOSE GREGORIO COVA PACHECO

• E-mail: jose.cova.pacheco@gmail.com

• **Cel:** +57 (304) 3661805

• Skype: jose.cova.p

PROFILE

Logistics and Supply chain Master and International Business Professional with five years of experience. Professional with high responsibility and ability to participate in research and development projects, always willing to make the application of my knowledge allows improving any management. Working and studying in Sweden, France and Colombia provides me of a very high ability to adapt to new companies, cultures and different roles.

Soft Skills

- Customer Oriented
- Team player
- Strategic Thinking
- Entrepreneurial
 - Multi-Tasking

Hard Skills

- Communication
- BusinessDevelopment
- Market Research
- Relationship Management

Technical Skills

- OperationsPlanning
- Analysis
- Languages
- Microsoft Office

Languages

- Native Spanish
- Fluent English
- Fluent French

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Purchasing Coordinator

Protecciones Industriales PROTEGER S.A.S.

Barranguilla, Colombia May. 2014-2017

Proteger is a private company incorporated in simplified joint stock company focused on the wholesale of all kinds of machinery and industrial safety equipment

Key Activities and Main Accomplishments:

- Responsible of the short, middle and long term strategies for the product portfolio of safety equipments.
- Develop the annual execution plan, by proposing a clear definition of the business growth drivers, Logistics KPIs and must win battles of our brands to accelerate productgrowth.
- Lead promotional efforts of the sales force (promotional and institutional) to achieve annual sales targets.
- Maximize effectiveness on delivery and after sale service, likewise cost savings by 40%.
- I managed to start a project in which we worked hand in hand with 4 suppliers from China, increasing operational performance by 35% and return on investment by 55%.
- Run and operate a customer support program , achieving + 20 public tenders in 12 months, increasing the income average +25%.
- Launched a new product in hands safety equipments, achieving 7% of Market Share in the first six months.

Accounting Coordinator

Coofamcov Ltd.

Barranquilla, Colombia Jun. 2013- Apr. 2014

Oversee the process of collecting money and ensuring the reconciliation of debts with customers.

Key Activities and Main Accomplishments:

- Analyze needs & gaps in the finance area to develop training solutions aligned to sales competencies.
- 15% increase in the income of the company during the same year
- Negotiate successfully with the area of finance an expansion of the DSO (Days Sales Outstanding), to achieve the sales target at the end of the year (2013).
- Collaborate with internal and external partners to drive strategic training initiatives to achieve sustainable business results.
- Active participation in training team meetings, and strategy goal activities.

Commercial Attaché Assistant

Embassy of Colombia to Sweden,

Stockholm, Sweden Aug. 2012- Jan. 2013

Key Activities and Main Accomplishments:

- Analysis of the systems of Government, political systems and political parties, and trade policy of Sweden, Finland, Iceland and Denmark.
- The participation of Nordic companies, especially Swedish, in the Colombian market in different areas was increased by 12%.
- In 2012 it was able to reach the largest number of foreign direct investment to Colombia by 51.92 million dollars mainly in the area of mining and infrastructure.
- In this same year it was achieved an investment in Colombia by more than 1,300 million pesos from the company ORIFLAME, a leading Swedish company in direct sale of cosmetics.
- Manage strategic relationships with swede enterprises to form networks of influence for the Business Unit.

Business Advisory

Zeiky PROCOLOMBIA,

Barranquilla, Colombia Jun. 2009 – Dec. 2009.

Foreign Trade Advice.

Key Activities and Main Accomplishments:

- Prepare monthly presentation for the commercial committee to evaluate the results of commercial KPI's and define action plans.
- Support the marketing department, delivering information for decision- making, establishing market potential and competition.
- Responsible for the management of the database of potential clients, appointments, follow-up and elaboration of performance indicators.

EDUCATION

Master of Logistics of International Good Transport

Universidad del Norte Barranquilla, Colombia 2014-2015

Master of Sciences of Management.

Groupe Sup de Co Montpellier, France 2011-2012.

Bachelor of International Business

Universidad del Norte Barranquilla, Colombia 2008-2012.

WORKSHOPS & CERTIFICATES

Unctad Annual Study Tour to International Organizations for Colombian Universities United Nations, Geneva, Switzerland.

I International Corporate responsibility workshop Barranquilla, Colombia.

Seminar: Foreign Exchange System for Export Services Zeiky, Procolombia.